Gautam Rajeev Singh

Backend Engineer | Python Developer Raipur gautamsingh1997@gmail.com linkedin: /singhgautam7 +91 7415310070

About Me

I am an efficient and confident coding enthusiast with demonstrated experience of working in the backend and database planning. My experience helped me develop expert knowledge of Python. I am highly motivated to continue learning and improving my craft.

Work History

CodeNicely

Software Development Engineer Oct 2019 - Currrent

- Developed back-end from scratch on one of CodeNicely's biggest project.
- Fashioned web-applications as per client's demands and expectations.
- Spearheaded a team of 4 people to design and develop projects on different platorms.
- Managed clients personally and noted their feedbacks for delopment and quality assurance
- Mentored new django developers in the company.
- Interviewed new applicants and shortlisted them as per company's requirements.

BYJU's- The Learning App

Business Development Associate Internship- Jan 2019 - Apr 2019 Fulltime- Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

- Regularly and effectively met warm calling targets, 2.5-3 hours call time per day.
- Accelerated company's growth by achieving a target revenue of 1.5L-2L per week.

Educational Background

SSGI - FET, Junwani, Bhilai 2015 - 2019 Computer Science & Engineering - 70%

K.V. no.1 Raipur 2015 Senior Secondary(12th) - 87.6%

Technical Skills

- Expert: Django, Python, Pycharm, DRF
- Intermediate: C++, C, VS Code, Ubuntu, HTML, CSS, Data Structures
- Learning: Vue JS

Projects undertaken

HealthPotli

A medicine and health products delivery platform

Jan 2020 - Currrent

- Collaborated on the development of new software interfaces for HealthPotli
- Re-engineered the database architecture along with teammates which could manage 42k customers with 45k products.
- Worked on technologies like REST API's, Web Sockets, bootstrap, cronjob, caching etc.
- Created and maintained backend for all platforms, i.e. web, android and iOS.
- Optimized queries to work with dynamic data and put less load on the server.
- Documented api's with swagger for better team communication and understanding.
- Handled background tasks to make sure reliable inventory is managed for all 50k products.